Is everyone here?
人齐了
Yeah, everyone's here.
齐了
The meeting's over.
散会
What's that supposed to mean?
什么意思啊
Beats me.
我哪知道
Let's go.
走吧
Seriously,
我告诉你
this guy is odd.
这位老莫名其妙
To prevent
为了再避免
this from happening again,
这种情况的出现
I'll add everyone
稍后我会添加
on WeChat,
每位同事的微信
and I'll set up a work group
我们建立一个工作群
so that it gets the attention of everyone.
请大家随时关注
If anyone's late
如果再出现这种
or leaves early again,
迟到或早退的情况
I'll leave it to
我们按照
company rules to decide.
行里的规定来处理
Meeting dismissed.
散会吧
This VIP is quite something,
这关系户有点意思啊
really knows how to put on airs.
挺能摆谱
Looks all harmless
看着像只
like a sheep,
人畜无害的小绵羊
but just now
刚才那一出
acted more like
倒唱出了点
a big bad wolf.
大灰狼的意思
I didn't expect
没想到
to get so freaked out
隐恋的第一天
by a little name badge
被一个小工牌
on our first day
吓得我心脏
of secret dating.
都快跳出来了
Really?
是吗
Xiaoning,
我怎么觉得
you seemed pretty chill,
小涂好像心态很稳啊
especially at the convenience store.
尤其是在便利店里
You were super quick to react.
反应神速
No way,
哪里
I almost tripped.
我明明差点摔跤的呀
We need
我们俩这种关系呢
to stay alert
就是一定要
in this
时刻保持警惕
kind of relationship with you,
以后呢
always...
更是要
Be on our toes...
警钟长鸣
Right.
对
Mr. Ji,
纪总
how's your first day
你第一天
in the BDD?
来拓展一部
What's your impression?
有什么感受啊
Honestly,
其实说真的
on this first day,
这第一天
I feel like there are quite a few issues
我觉得需要解决的问题
that to be sorted out.
还不少
Is it about the colleagues?
是同事们吗
Don't move,
别动
I'll wash the dishes today,
今天的碗我来刷
and handle the housework.
家务也都我来做
From now on, I'll do it on
以后呢
Mon, Wed, and Fri. The rest is yours.
我一三五你二四六
On Sundays, we both rest.
周日咱们俩休息
Clear division of labor,
这样分工明确
clear boundaries.
界限感比较明确才好
Do we need boundaries after work?
下班时间用分那么清楚
Yes, we do.
当然要分得清楚了
This way, if something happens,
这样万一遇到什么事呢
it's muscle memory,
我们这就是肌肉反应
and it won't be obvious to others.
不容易被人发现
Makes sense.
有道理
So today, you wash the dishes,
那今天你刷碗
I'll clean up.
我来收拾
Sure,
好
I got it.
我来
What's wrong?
怎么了
Nothing,
没事
my new shoes rubbing a bit.
新买的鞋有点卡脚
It'll be fine in a couple of days.
卡两天就好了
Here, let me.
来 给我
There you go.
给你
Thanks?
谢谢
So, what happened next?
然后呢
Nothing.
没有然后啊
Nothing?
没有然后
You look exhausted.
看你那一脸疲惫的样子
Ling Weiyi,
凌惟依
if your brain
你的脑袋里
had a screen,
要是能装个显示屏
it'd be covered with mosaics.
肯定满屏的马赛克
What are you thinking?
想什么呢
By "nothing," I mean
没有然后的意思是
he went to his room,
他回他的房间
I went to mine.
我回我的房间
We're good, no interruptions.
我们各自安好互不打扰
Tu Xiaoning,
涂筱柠
are you monks
你俩这干吗呢
in spiritual practice?
带发修行啊
If you're serious,
以结婚为前提的恋爱
you need to
就是要全方位地
check everything out about him,
考察到位
and the most important thing
最重要的
is physical chemistry.
当然就是身体素质了
We're eating,
吃饭呢
can you stop
你那些黄色废料
with the dirty talk?
能不能收一收
I'm just trying to help.
我是为你好
I asked you here
我找你来呢
to get your opinion.
就想让你帮我参谋参谋
At this stage,
我们俩
is it normal
现在这个阶段
for this to happen
发生这样的事情
between us?
合理吗
Not normal,
不合理
not at all.
非常地不合理
You've already kissed,
你们俩亲都亲了
why not take it further
为什么不趁热打铁
while things are hot?
事半功倍一下
You might
说不定
end up with
还能来一个
some fiery passion,
干柴烈火花前月下
a romantic evening,
你侬我侬
and unforgettable moments.
回味无穷呀
Such a waste, really.
可惜呀 可惜
Our department's first meeting
今早上班我们召开
will be held this morning.
部门第一次会议
Sorry, I have to go.
不好意思我得先走了
Duty calls.
我的饭碗在召唤我
Can't stay for your lecture.
不能听你讲课了
Next time.
下次
Always in a rush.
又这么赶
Don't forget to finish these
那你记得这些
before your meeting.
吃完再开会啊
Didn't those shoes rub your feet?
你这鞋那天不说磨脚吗
Why are you still wearing them?
怎么还穿着啊
They're fine now.
现在不磨了
They've softened up.
软得很
See you.
走了
Mr. Ji,
纪总
I currently
截至目前呢
have
我这边的存量客户
12 clients,
一共十二户
90% of them
百分之九十
are small private businesses,
都是民营小企业
and they're
他们现在
all repaying as planned.
都是正常还款的状态
Mr. Ji,
纪总我这边
I have 10 clients,
存量客户是十户
and my goal is to increase the deposit
目标是明年第一季度
by 15% by the end
将 增加新的存款
of the first quarter next year.
百分之十五
I have 5 clients,
我这边存量客户是五户
aiming to boost the volume of deposits
目标明年第一季度
by 10%
将新的存款
in the first quarter next year.
增加百分之十
Mr. Ji,
纪总我这边的
I have 9 clients,
存量客户是九户
80% are small businesses,
小型企业占百分之八十
and 20%t are medium-sized.
中型企业占百分之二十
My goal is to increase the number of
目标是明年可以把
medium and large business clients
中大型企业的客户量
by 15% by next year.
增加到百分之十五
I have
我这边存量客户呢
32 clients,
是三十二户
60% are small businesses,
小企业占百分之六十
30% are
大中型客户是
medium to large clients,
百分之三十
and 10% are government-related.
政府类有百分之十
My goal for the first quarter next year
目标是明年的第一季度
is to increase derived deposits
将派生的存款
by 30%.
增加到百分之三十
30%, huh?
目标百分之三十
That's pretty ambitious.
还挺理想的
We still need to review
不过还是要梳理一下
the interest costs and composite returns
在手客户的利率成本
of our current clients.
和综合回报
Starting from the coming week,
下周开始
I'll go visit them one by one with you.
我跟你逐一去拜访
All right.
好
Manager Zhao,
赵经理
you have 18 clients,
在手客户十八家
80% government,
八成是政府
and 20% private.
两成是民营
What are your
我想听一下你的
career plans?
职业规划
My plan is to grow
我的规划就是
and excel in my role
在客户经理的岗位上
as a client manager.
做大做强
With just 18 clients?
就靠这十八个客户啊
I think it's quite a lot.
我觉得不少了
Mr. Ji,
纪总
you're new to the BDD,
你刚来拓展一部
so you might not know.
可能不太了解
Government-related clients
政府的客户多
bring more deposits,
名下的存款就多
which is the most practical.
这是最实际的
The government is heavily
国家现在
supporting private enterprises now,
在大力扶持民营企业
and all banks
所有的银行
are making structural transformation.
也都在做结构调整
Given this trend, you have
按照这个趋势
only 4 private businesses,
你只负责四家民营企业
and 1 is a bad loan.
还有一户是不良
Are you happy with that?
你自己满意吗
I think it's fine.
我觉得挺好的呀
All right,
行
I'll work harder.
我努力
"Working harder" is something
努力这种话
you say to yourself.
是说给自己听的
I'm result-oriented.
我看的是结果
I'll go out and visit clients
那一会儿散会以后
right after the meeting.
我就出去跑客户
From this month on, add 1 new
从这个月开始
private business client each month.
每月新增一家民企客户
I'll try my best.
我尽力
Is 1 client a month
一个月一户
really that hard for you?
对你来说很困难吗
Mr. Ji,
纪总
whatever you say,
您说什么
I'll do.
我就去执行什么
Tu Xiaoning,
涂筱柠
what business
我想问一下
are you handling now?
你现在负责什么业务
Corporate admissions,
企业准入
ratings,
评级
bank drafts,
银行兑汇票
domestic letters of credit,
国内信用证
and discount processes.
贴现的业务流程
I'm asking about your business,
我问的是业务
not processes.
不是流程
If you can't complete
半年的时间
the necessary business assessments
如果你没法完成
within six months,
转正必需的业务考核
someone else
你的位置
will take your place.
有人来替代
Got it, Mr. Ji.
好的纪总
You wanted to be
是你自己要求
treated equally.
一视同仁的
Don't mess up, Tu Xiaoning.
不能输啊 涂筱柠
Hi,
您好
can you tell me
那个
how to get to
请问一下
the loan department
代瑞银行的
at Bank of Dairui?
贷款部门怎么走
Do you have an appointment?
请问 您有预约吗
My friend works here.
我朋友在这儿上班
I came to meet him.
我有事儿找他
I called,
刚才给他打电话
but he didn't answer.
他没接
Can I
我
go up and wait for him?
我能不能上去等他
Sorry,
不好意思啊
our policy requires visitors
我们这儿规定访客
to be escorted.
必须要有人接才能进
Please wait
要不您先去休息区
in the lounge.
稍坐等待一下
Okay, thanks.
好 谢谢啊
Security!
保安
The man in black is breaking in!
有个穿黑衣服的硬闯
That meeting
刚才那会开得
made me so mad.
我这一肚子火
Me too.
我也是
Zhao's so patient.
你说赵哥的脾气那么好
If it were me,
你要换作我
I'd have flipped the table.
我早给他把桌子给掀了
Excuse me,
你好
does your
请问一下那个
department handle
代瑞的贷款项目
Dairui's loan projects?
是咱们部门负责吗
I have a query.
我有个问题想咨询一下
Hold on, please.
你先稍等一会儿啊
We don't handle
先别咨询你这
external business here.
我们这儿不办对外业务
You need to go to
你要办业务
the main hall,
得去那个大厅
get a number,
去排号
and wait.
排完号之后在那儿办
Also, now isn't a good time.
而且这个时间也不行
Yes.
是
Try later.
稍晚点吧
You always say
你们动不动就说
there's no time,
没有时间
but you have time now, don't you?
现在有时间了吧
No...
不是
what are you doing?
你干什么
No, this time...
不是 它这个时间
You... sir...
你 大哥
please calm down.
您先冷静一点
Let's talk.
有话好好说行吗
Put the knife down.
把刀放下
The time for talking is over!
好好说话的时间过去了
You... put the knife...
你 你把那个刀
Has anyone even listened to me?
有人理过我吗
Xiaoning?
小涂
Hello, sir.
你好这位先生
I'm Tu Xiaoning, an assistant
我是客户经理助理
client manager.
涂筱柠
Here's my badge.
这是我的工牌你看一下
What can I help you with?
您有什么诉求吗
You can tell me.
跟我说
I'll do my best
我一定会努力
to assist you.
帮你解决的
We all will.
我们都会
Yes, yes.
对 对 对
Qianliyuan.
千里缘
Qianliyuan introduced me
千里缘介绍我
to an
办理了一款
88,000 yuan dating loan.
八万八千块钱的相亲贷
I gave the money
我拿了这八万八千块钱
to my girlfriend
给了我在千里缘上边的
from Qianliyuan,
相亲的女朋友
and she
我女朋友
ran off with it.
拿了这笔钱跑了
Now your bank
现在你们代瑞银行
wants me to repay the loan.
催着我来还这笔钱
It's unfair.
我觉着不公平
Why should I pay for the money
凭什么她拿钱跑了
she took and ran away with?
你们让我来还这笔钱
Qianliyuan,
千里缘是吧
I know.
我知道
A dating company.
一家相亲公司
Yes,
对
they guaranteed
就是他们
the loan,
在中间做的担保
which is why I took it.
我才贷的这笔钱
Sir,
大哥
this loan was arranged
这是那个千里缘
by Qianliyuan...
给你办的
You...
你
When you convinced me to take the loan,
你们让我贷款的时候
everything sounded perfect.
说得天花乱坠的
Now that there's an issue,
现在出了事儿
you don't care?
就不管了是吗
No, we won't ignore it.
没有 绝对不会
We will never turn a blind eye.
绝对不会不管
I'm going to
我今天
die here today
今天就死在这儿
to show you!
给你们看看
Calm down, calm down!
冷静 冷静 冷静
Cool it, man!
你冷静
Call the police, get security.
报警 叫保安
All right.
好
Stay safe.
你注意安全
Don't rush.
先别着急
This may take some time.
这需要走流程的
Please put the knife down,
你先把刀放下
and let's talk.
咱慢慢说
You...
你
you
你现在
cancel it
马上去
right now!
快给我注销了
Cancel it immediately!
马上就销
Okay, okay!
好 好 好
Do you
那你 你还
remember your
你还记得你的
loan contract number?
贷款合同编码吗
I'll find it for you
我现在马上给你
right now.
我给您找一下
Contract number?
编码
It's okay if you don't remember.
不记得也没关系
We can use facial recognition.
我们可以人脸识别
Just look at this camera
你对着这个镜头
for the scan.
人脸识别一下
Right.
是
Look here.
看 看 看
Over here.
看这儿
Scammers!
骗子
You're scammers!
都是骗子
Security!
保安
Take him down!
把他给我抓起来
You're bleeding.
出血了
It's okay.
没事
Are you all right?
你没关系吧
Xiaoning,
小涂
you really are a hero.
不愧是大堂干出来的
That was impressive.
女中豪杰
No, it was thanks to Ji...
没有还是多亏了纪
Mr. Ji.
纪总
Luckily,
幸亏
he acted quickly.
他动作快
It was indeed
当时那种情况
a dangerous situation.
确实挺危险的
I wanted to help too,
其实我也想帮忙
but I wasn't there.
刚好不在
But
不过
you shouldn't side with him
你可不能因为这件事情
just because of this incident.
跟别人一条战线了
Who is related to Ji Yuheng?
谁是纪昱恒的家属
Doctor, how is he?
医生他怎么样了
The wound is not deep,
伤口不深
but it's quite large.
但是面积比较大
We've done initial treatment,
我们做了初步的处理
but he needs proper rest.
接下来就要好好地休养
During recovery,
休养期间
he shouldn't eat spicy food,
不能吃辛辣的
and the wound mustn't get wet.
伤口不能碰水
Why are you here?
你怎么来了
How are you?
你怎么样了
I'm fine.
没事
You've got a lot of guts.
胆子变大了呀
Aren't you afraid they'll find out?
不怕他们发现了
Let me see your hand.
我看看你的手
It's nothing.
没事的
Really,
你也真是的
what if he had used more force
那小高万一再使点劲
and seriously
把你弄得皮开肉绽的
injured you?
怎么办呀
Better me than you.
那也比划在你身上强吧
I'm a man;
我一个大男人
a little injury is nothing.
受点伤没什么
But you,
倒是你
I haven't even asked you yet.
我还没说你呢
Why did you step in
人家都站着不动
while the others were backing out?
你干吗上去应付啊
I've been in the lobby for three years.
我在大堂待了三年
I've seen this kind of thing a lot.
这种事情见得多了
It's become a natural reaction.
已经形成自然反应了
I'm used to it.
习惯了
What did the doctor say?
医生怎么说呀
Do you need to stay for observation?
需要留院观察吗
Are you still in pain?
你还疼不疼啊
No pain,
不疼
just need an IV drip.
一会儿再输个液
A few hours
大夫说
of observation should be enough.
留观几个小时就好了
All right.
好
How's his situation?
小高那边情况怎么样了
Jing called the police.
静姐打电话报警了
He should have been taken away.
小高应该被抓走了
If they
一会儿
go back to the company,
他们要先回公司的话
I'll go with them
我跟他们一起回
and find a chance to return later.
然后找机会折回来
No need,
不用
it's work time.
现在是上班时间
Don't you remember the agreement
忘了昨天晚上那个协议
we signed last night?
怎么签的了
Mr. Ji.
纪总
Is your arm okay?
你胳膊没事吧
It's fine.
没事
The doctor has already taken care of it.
大夫都已经处理完了
That's good to hear.
那就好
Where's Xiaoning?
小涂呢
She was
她刚才不是
just with us.
还跟我们在一块吗
Right,
对呀
let me call her.
我给她打个电话
Is Xiaoning here too?
小涂也在呢
She's not answering.
不接电话
Maybe she went back
可能公司有事
to the company.
先回去了吧
Then we should
那正好
head back too.
我们也回吧
The doctor said
刚才医生交代了说
you need to stay for observation.
你还得留院观察一下
Manager Rao, you go back first,
那饶经理先回
and Manager Zhao will stay with me.
赵经理留下来陪我
Fine.
都行
Want to have a drink tonight?
晚上一起喝一点
I'm not as carefree as you guys.
我没你们潇洒
Oh, I bought an Americano and a latte.
对了 买了美式和拿铁
Which one do you want?
你要喝哪个
Latte, please.
拿铁吧
Latte, here you go.
拿铁行 来
You should head back.
你先回去吧
All right,
行
I'll go.
那我过去了
Why did she come to the hospital?
她怎么会来医院
Are you okay?
没事吧
Are you okay? Were you scared just now?
刚才吓着了
A bit, yeah.
确实是有点
Must have seen a lot of troublemakers
之前在大堂工作
working in the lobby before, right?
来闹事的人没少见吧
It's rare to see someone with a knife.
但动刀子的还是少见
True.
确实
Consider it an eye-opener.
你就当开开眼吧
But you were too reckless just now.
不过刚才你太莽撞了
And
还有啊
you shouldn't have shown him
你就不应该给他看
your badge.
你的工牌
What if
你怎么不想一想
he filed a complaint
你还没转正
and you lost your job?
万一他一个投诉
You haven't even been confirmed yet.
你下岗了怎么办
I didn't think that far.
我当时确实没想那么多
I just wanted to help solve the problem.
就想帮他解决问题来着
So, what happened
那 那个小高
to Gao?
怎么处理了呀
It's up to the police.
看警察怎么说吧
But he really
但那人真是的
shouldn't have pulled a knife,
再冲动他也不应该
no matter how impulsive he was.
动刀子啊
And Mr. Ji,
还有那个纪总也是
he's new to our department
刚来我们部门
and acted too impulsively too.
做事也是太冲动了
What if
你说万一真的伤着他
he had been seriously hurt?
有个三长两短怎么办
Who would take responsibility?
这责任谁负
Jing,
静姐
what is this dating loan?
那个相亲贷是什么呀
I didn't know our bank
我怎么不知道
offered such a service.
咱们行有这个业务
The dating loan
那个相亲贷
is a term
也就是这两年
created by
相亲行业
the matchmaking service providers
自己包装出来的
in the past couple of years,
一个名词
similar to
跟咱们银行这两年
our bank's
做的消费贷
consumer loans.
差不多
It was handled by Manager Jiang before.
之前一直是江总在管
But Manager Jiang
但是江总
has been fired, right?
不是已经被开除了吗
Yes, but he
这个江总虽然被开除了
wasn't the
但是之前
only one
这个业务经手的
involved in this business.
可不止他一个人
Consumer loans are a legitimate business
消费贷是总行
promoted by the head office,
推广的业务
not illegal or against the rules.
又不违规又不违法的
As for what customers do with the money,
至于人家客户贷了款
getting married or funerals,
去娶媳妇还是办丧事
that's their business.
我也管不着
Consumer loans
这消费贷
are legitimate,
确实是正规的业务
but that doesn't mean
但并不代表你们
there were no irregularities
经手的过程当中
in the process.
不存在任何违规行为
Did you
充分了解
fully understand the customers'
客户的诉求和情况
needs and situations
明确告知合约的
and have you explained
相关规定
the contract terms?
有做到吗
To make it even worse,
那我说得再严重一点
if someone
如果说
secretly collaborated
有人私底下
with matchmaking platforms
跟相亲平台合作
to deceive
以欺骗
or induce borrowers
或者是诱导的方式
to take loans,
来促成客户的贷款
like today's case
就像今天那人说的
and took kickbacks...
从中拿到一些回扣
Mr. Ji,
纪总
you can't just say that.
这话可不能乱说
It was approved by Manager Jiang,
业务是江总批的
He brought in the lenders.
客户是江总拉的
I was just
我就只是一个
doing the legwork.
跑腿干活的
You can't
这屎盆子
pin this on me.
总不能扣我头上吧
I'm not saying it's you.
我没说是你
But Manager Zhao,
不过赵经理
as the handler,
你是经办人
you need to clear your name
要想清清白白
by thoroughly investigating
就得费点心思
this matter.
把这件事情给查清楚
Are you not up for it?
不想干了
Mr. Ji,
纪总啊
you just
您啊
joined us
是刚来我们
and haven't been here long
基层单位时间短
so you might not understand
可能还不太清楚
that dealing with people
这人和人
in everyday life
平时生活里打交道
inevitably involves complications,
都免不了有是非
especially when we're
更别说
dealing with
咱们整天跟人手里的钱
other people's money.
打交道了
It's commonplace
遇见几个不讲理的
to run into
胡搅蛮缠的
some unreasonable pricks.
那再正常不过了
If you want clarity on everything,
要是每个都查清楚
we shouldn't bother working our asses off.
那大家伙别干业务了
Should just go be a cop.
都去破案得了
Alright, answer me this.
那我问你个问题啊
Is this so called
你觉得从我们行里
"blind date loan"
以相亲贷这种名义
issued from our bank
放出去的贷款
an isolated case?
是个例吗
If there's a
如果这件事情
massive blow-up,
大范围爆雷
the Main Branch will step in.
总行一定会介入
Then this
那今天的这场谈话
stops being
就不是
a problem between us.
你我二人之间的了
Fine.
行
You want me to investigate?
不就是让我去查吗
Let's do it then.
查呗
You stay here and rest.
那你自个儿歇着吧
I'm off.
我去了
Hey, doc.
医生
Um...
那个
my friend's on his
我朋友还有一瓶药
last bag of IV.
没有输完呢
Please keep an eye on him.
辛苦您受累盯着点
I gotta go.
我还有事得先走了
Don't hold back when you remove the needle.
拔针的时候疼点
He can take the pain.
没关系
Call Rao Jing.
打电话给饶静
Calling Rao Jing.
正在呼叫饶静
Ms Rao.
饶经理
Speak.
说
There's a name card
我那办公桌上
of a client on my desk.
有一张客户名片
Can I trouble you to take a picture
你受累拍个照
of it and send it to me?
发给我一下呗
You in the office right?
你在公司呢吧
I got a dog
我们家养了条狗
and it's having a bit of
然后呢那个狗最近
a diarrhea.
有点拉稀
I gotta head back
我回去啊
pick up the messes
得给它收拾烂摊子
and wipe its ass.
给它擦屁股
Gotta go.
挂了
Hey!
你什么意思啊
What're you on about?
擦什么屁股
Hey.
喂
Are we not heading back to the office?
咱们不回公司啊
Of course not.
回什么公司
I'm not letting slip
这么好的时机
a great opportunity like this.
一定要抓住
This whole "blind date loan" thing has turned into a giant mess.
相亲贷这事闹得挺大的
If she handles it well,
她要是处理得好
she has something to show for it
还能在领导面前
before the boss.
搏个表现
Quite a plan
这算盘
she's got.
她倒是打得挺响
You were in the drama
之前在学校
club back in school, right?
参加过话剧社吧
Follow my lead.
一会儿陪我演出戏
That was fast.
挺快啊
Right back at you.
你也不慢啊
Looking for a date?
找对象吗
Have you filled in the forms?
填过资料了吗
We've got 90 percent
我们这儿覆盖了全市
of the city's singletons
百分之九十的
signed up here.
单身男青年女呢
There's definitely someone for you.
肯定有您喜欢的
Sir, you must be
这位先生年纪
eager to get a date.
该着急了吧
We'll offer you a 20 percent discount.
会费给你打个八折
Miss Tu?
涂小姐啊
I didn't recognize you for a second.
您来了也不跟我说一声
I've got a really
我最近手里呀
good match for you.
有一个成色特别好的
Same age as you.
跟您同岁
Studied abroad.
海归
Works in a bank.
在银行系统上班
Name's Ji...
叫 纪
Have you issued
上次我让你
the invoice I told you to?
给我开的发票开了吗
No?
没开
Let's do it now. Come on.
现在赶紧补一个 快
Sir, what's your type?
先生您喜欢什么样的
We have it all.
我们这儿应有尽有
It's quite a selection.
什么样的都有
Let me know your preferences.
您喜欢什么样您跟我说
I'll set you up.
过来跟你介绍
Here, have a look.
你看一看 你看一看
Take a good look.
你好好 看一看
Come on.
走
Hurry.
快 快 快
Miss Tu,
涂小姐
was it invoice you were saying?
您刚刚说发票
How come
我怎么
I don't have any recollection of it?
记 不记得有个发票
Sorry,
不好意思
I must've remembered it wrong.
是我记错了
It's ok.
没事
I'm telling you,
我跟您说啊
if a different agency promises you someone handsome
这其他人要说帅的
they're probably lying.
那您都不能信
But if I tell you
我们这儿
I've got a handsome guy,
我说帅的
he's
那一定是
as handsome as they come.
万里挑一的那个尖
Here, Miss Tu,
来 涂小姐
have a look.
您看看
You can't put them up here.
不能放在这儿啊
What was that?
涂小姐 您说什么
Why don't you
要不
go have some rest?
您去休息一下
I'll show
我到处转转
myself around.
我自己走走
This is no trouble.
我不忙
I'm going
我跟您说啊
to find you his file.
我要去给您找资料去
I promise you'll like it.
保证您喜欢
Come.
来
Follow me.
跟我走啊
Miss Tu,
涂小姐
have some coffee and
您先喝杯咖啡
take a break.
稍微休息一下
I'll go get the file.
我去拿资料啊
Thanks.
谢谢
Thank god we haven't got the marriage certificate.
幸亏没领证
Otherwise
这要是领了证
they'd stick that on the wall.
还不得把结婚证挂墙上
Scared the shit out of me.
吓死我了
Don't you worry. We've got
姐你放心我们这边绝对
the best of best here.
都是最优质的人
Ma'am.
女士
Did you come
您是和涂小姐
with Miss Tu?
一起来的那位吧
Yes.
对
I've got this.
这边有我
You can go.
你先去忙
Ok.
好
Here, this way.
来 这边请
So...
我跟您说啊
I had a quick look earlier.
我刚翻了一下
They used to study at the same middle school.
他俩居然是一个中学的
It's like it's meant to be.
真是太有缘分了
As far as I'm concerned,
要我说啊
these two
他俩这种
can get married right now.
就应该立马领证结婚
Even a one-day delay
晚一天啊
would be defying fate.
都是对这缘分的不尊重
Have a seat.
您坐
Fate?
缘分
What fate?
什么缘分
Miss Tu,
涂小姐
this is the file on Mr. Ji,
这是跟您提过的纪先生
the one I was telling you about.
他的资料
Come on, check out the man
快来看看您这
fate has in store for you.
命定的缘分
No, no, no.
不 不 不用了
There's no need.
不用了
Three.
三
Two.
二
One.
一
So? What do you think?
怎么样
He looks...
挺
like a nice guy...
挺纯朴的
Let's find out more.
咱可以再了解了解
I don't think
我觉得
I'm good enough for him.
我配不上人家
No such thing.
怎么会呢
It's ok.
没事
Let's keep looking.
咱再看看啊
Why don't you show me instead?
我来了解一下吧
Come in.
进来
Sir.
老师
Yuheng.
昱恒
Come.
来 来 来
Come on over.
赶紧过来
How's your injury?
伤得怎么样了
Is it bad?
要紧吗
It's not a big deal.
没什么大碍
Come. Sit.
来 坐
A knife attack
都动刀子了
has never happened before
这在拓展部呀
at BDD.
还是头一回
My apologies.
真是抱歉
I didn't expect things
我也没想到事情
to turn out like this.
会发展成这样
I've already sent Zhao
另外我已经让赵经理
to look it up.
去处理这件事了
We should
应该很快
have an answer soon.
就能有一个结论
It's a legacy
都是陈年烂事
of your predecessor.
道什么歉呀
Why, though, are you
倒是那个赵方刚
still using that Zhao?
你怎么还敢用他呢
Granted, Jiang is the one to blame here.
虽然这事错在老江
But Zhao did all the dirty work.
但毕竟他是主要经手人
You still trust him
你说你这个时候
to undo the damage?
还指望他亡羊补牢吗
Actually, sir, that's
老师其实我过来找您啊
why I'm here.
也是为了跟您说这事
I went through all the consumer loan
这两天我仔细看了一下
contracts the past few days.
那批消费贷的所有合同
Zhao wasn't
其实赵方刚
directly involved in much of it.
直接经手的部分很有限
I've also
另外这两天
been watching him
我也观察了一下
at work.
他的工作状态
He might
他这个人
look like a slacker.
看起来是懒散了点
But he treats
实际干起活来
his job seriously.
一点都不含糊
Detail-oriented too.
还很细致
On top of that,
另外还有一点很重要
he's got the highest number
他的政府客户数量
of government clients
放在整个拓展部
in the entire department.
那都是遥遥领先
All this shows
这说明他这个人
he's good at his job
工作能力很强
I don't question his ability.
我倒不质疑他的能力
But the issue is
但是问题是
is he on your side?
他跟你是一条心吗
I don't really mind
他是不是跟我一心
if he's not on my side.
其实我没有很在意
What I want
我更在意的是
is for him to contribute
他对整个拓展一部
to the department.
有没有贡献
He's the
他是这个
operator on these loans.
消费贷的经办人
He wants this resolved
他一定会比其他任何人
ASAP
都迫切地希望
more than anyone.
这件事情赶快解决
So, he'll get to
所以也会为了
the bottom of this for his
自己的饭碗
own job if not anything else.
把这件事情给查清楚
"Blind date loan?"
相亲贷
That's a thing?
真有这种东西
So Gao wasn't lying to me.
这小高还真没骗我
Neither of us
大家都是
has the money to get married.
缺钱结婚的老爷们
He was able to
你说他
get a load for the bride price.
他能贷出彩礼
I can't fall behind, can I.
我也不能比他差吧
Exactly.
当然
This product of ours
我们这款贷款啊
is nondiscriminatory.
不挑客户的
It doesn't require you to
而且也不需要您
provide qualifications either.
提供任何资质
Is this some
你们不会是那种
kind of usury?
私人的高利贷吧
It's not. You have my word.
保证不是高利贷
Proper loan from the bank.
是银行系统的正规贷款
Perks of using our flatform.
咱们平台的特殊福利呢
We've got
咱们这儿啊
connections.
有人
Great.
这敢情好
But
那我
what if
我万一要是
I can't pay it back?
还不上呢
For us folks,
咱们小老百姓
100 grand for bride price
这个彩礼顶破天
tops.
也就十来万
That amount is nothing
对于人家银行来说
for the banks.
算得了什么呀
If I
那
apply for the loan
我要是通过你们
through you,
做贷款的话
can the dating service
我那个婚介服务费
fees be exempted?
能不能包含在里面呀
Non members
这外面的人啊
have to pay
是要付
5 percent for the service fees.
五个点的服务费呢
But our members
但咱们的会员
only have to pay 3 percent.
只要三个点
A mere 3 percent
三个点而已呀
and your marriage affairs are all sorted.
您的人生大事都解决了
You're right.
可不是吗
With the money problem sorted,
这问题要是解决了
I'll be one
那我通往婚姻
big step
最大的一道坎儿
closer to marriage.
那不就踏平了吗
Oh, right, which bank
那你们是和哪家银行
do you work with?
合作来着
Look,
你看
money don't come easily
我们老百姓挣点钱
to folks like us.
也不容易
I just want to see the contract.
我呢就是想看看合约
For peace of mind, you know.
图个心安
Dairui.
代瑞
You must've heard of it.
代瑞您肯定知道
What we provide
我们呀
is an agency contract.
提供是中介合约
So...
就是说
you are in
咱们这儿
very good connections
跟代瑞的关系
with Dairui.
特别得好
Will there be any problem if my sister
我姐要是在银行贷款了
applies for a loan here?
不会出现什么问题吧
And who do we blame
万一出现什么问题了
if there is?
说不清楚呀
Sorry to keep you waiting.
您久等了
Here.
来
Have a read.
您看一眼啊
Ok.
好嘞
I don't know if I can read this.
其实我也看不大懂
Look at
这么多文字
all this information.
密密麻麻的
Let me tell you.
我跟您说啊
When our boss started
我们老板呀
this company, it was a client manager
当初创业开公司的时候
surnamed Jiang from Dairui
找的就是代瑞一个
who processed
姓江的客户经理
his loan.
办的贷款
They got along
俩人处得呀
like brothers.
那是跟亲兄弟一样
Within only a couple of years,
后来这个人没几年
this guy became
就当上了
the department manager in charge of loans.
管贷款的部门经理了
Seeing that you're so tight with the bank,
你们关系这么铁
you must be offering a handsome sum
那你们肯定给那个经理
to that manager.
塞了不少好处
You don't
这年头
get anything for free these days.
亲兄弟还明算账呢
That's between the bosses.
这老板们的事儿
I'm not in a position to comment.
咱也不好说
But rest assured,
不过您放心啊
as long as this manager Jiang is still in place,
只要这个江总位置不倒
your loan
您这个贷款
will
肯定能顺利
come through.
给您贷出来的
Great.
太好了
Xiaoning,
筱柠
I'm finally getting
姐的个人问题
a handle on this.
终于解决了
Thank you.
谢谢你啊
You've been explaining things
你看说了大半天
all this time
耽误你这么久时间
and I still haven't
还没有跟你签
signed
代理找对象的
the dating contract.
合同呢
Why don't you
这样
bring it over?
你把合同拿过来
I'll sign both today.
今天呀我一起签了
No problem.
没问题
Wait here.
您稍等啊
I'll go get it now.
我现在就去拿
Ok.
好
You seem to be in a good mood.
赵经理挺高兴啊
Although I'm not responsible for
虽然相亲贷
this "blind date loan" fiasco,
这娄子跟我关系不大
as a Dairui employee,
但作为代瑞的一员
I have the obligation to
我有义务
help the bank wherever I can.
为行里分忧
Seems you
那看样赵经理
have got your hands on
应该是拿到了一些
some scraps of evidence.
边边角角的证据
But is that enough
那些证据够不够洗掉
to wash the stains off you?
赵经理身上的泥点子
I won't lie.
我也不怕告诉你
I did obtain
我确实是拿到了
some essential evidence.
核心证据
You, on the other hand,
倒是饶经理你
put on such a show,
戏台子搭这么大
trying to bury me under it.
想要淹我
I guess your little
怕不是要
plan didn't work.
竹篮打水喽
Don't flatter
赵方刚你也
yourself.
太把自己当回事儿了
You're already waist deep in the water.
你半条命都没了
why would I bother?
还差我这半瓢水啊
I'm the one who's helping the bank.
我才是为我行分忧
I don't care
你心里清不清楚
if you know.
不重要
I just want the bosses to know that.
领导心里清楚就行
Rao Jing.
饶静
Do you really not
你还有没有一点
care we're colleagues?
仅存的同事之情了
Climbing over my dead
抓着点机会
body to get what you want?
就踩着我往上爬
Well, that's
能踩着你往上爬呢
because I can.
是我饶静的本事
If you get the chance,
下次有机会
you may do the same.
你踩着我往上爬呀
Now that we have a winner,
既然呢咱们胜负已定
I'm done here.
就不必多言了
Honey.
姐姐
Here you are.
来了
I'm off then.
那我今天就
I have a date.
约会去了
Bye.
拜拜
You drive.
今天你开车
What did she say she was doing?
她刚说她要干什么去
On a date.
约会
Jing has a boyfriend.
静姐有男朋友
A much younger one at that.
还这么小
I'll be damned.
见鬼了
A vicious hag like her
这么狠毒的女人
has a boyfriend.
竟然有男朋友
Door Unlocked.
已开锁
Door locked.
已关锁
Ji Yuheng.
纪昱恒
What's going on?
你怎么了
Did you fall?
你没摔着吧
Come in.
进来吧
I thought you fell.
我以为你摔倒了呢
It's just my hand.
手受伤了
Can you help me change?
一会儿帮我换个衣服
Sure.
好
So...
我跟你说件事
I went to the dating company with Jing today
我今天跟静姐去千里缘
and saw
看到我们
the photos we used for dating
相亲时候的照片
on the wall.
挂在墙上
I took them down immediately
我立马把它们摘下来
so they didn't find out.
没有被他们发现
Did I do good?
算不算立功了
Certainly.
当然
So as a reward,
那作为回报的话
tonight...
今天晚上
Tonight?
晚上
Actually,
我想起来了
I'm meeting Ling Weiyi at the gym.
我约了凌惟依健身
I almost forgot.
我给忘了
I gotta go.
我得赶紧走了
I was gonna say I'll do the chores tonight.
我说今晚我做家务
I was the one who did something good.
帮忙的是我
Why did I run off
好像做错了事
like a guilty person?
落荒而逃的也是我
Don't you think
怎么一副
you overreacted?
没见过世面的样子啊
So your husband
不就是你们家纪先生
said "tonight."
说了句晚上吗
What's the big deal?
这又没什么
So...
说说看
does he have a great body?
未来老公身材怎么样
Like I'd know.
我哪敢看呀
We're newly
表面上
weds in name only.
我们俩是新婚夫妻
In truth,
那实际上
we're just roommates.
就是最普通的室友
But that doesn't mean
你把他当室友
he sees you as his roommate.
人家把你当室友了吗
A knife attack it was.
刀
He blocked a knife for you.
那可是替你挡刀
Ziwei took a knife for the Emperor
人紫薇给皇上挡刀
because he's her Father.
是因为人家是她皇阿玛
Are you his Mother?
你是他额娘
Bite me.
去你的
Think about it.
你想想看这事
Let's say this Ji Yuheng
就算这个纪昱恒
is
是
an upstanding guy.
勇敢正直好少年
But not every upstanding guy
那刀也不是一般随便人
will take a knife for you.
都敢接的吧
Averting danger is human nature.
避险是人性
As far as I'm concerned,
依我看
this future husband of yours
你这未来的老公
definitely has feelings for you.
对你可真不简单
Enough.
行了吧你
Rather than being such
煽我的风
an expert on my relationship.
点我的火厉害
Shouldn't you
管管你自己
reflect on your own?
想想自己怎么办
What about me?
我怎么了
I'm a single woman with all the freedom in the world.
我一单身自由女青年
Unlike someone,
可不像某些人
who's in a sea of trouble,
坠入了苦海
what with the future husband
又是什么未来老公
and the ex-boyfriend.
还又是前男友的
What now?
什么意思
Lu Sijing talked to you?
陆思靖找你了
He called me
他给我打电话
and asked
问我
what's the deal with you and Ji.
纪昱恒跟你是什么关系
What did you say?
你怎么说的
Said you were co-inhabitants of Earth.
同住地球村喽
Good answer.
聪明
It's a small city.
城市太小了
The fewer people know about it,
少一个人知道
the safer we are.
我们俩就安全一点
Do you still
你心里
think about that person?
还惦记那谁吗
Of course not.
当然没有
Listen.
你呀
Mr. Ji
既然你们家纪先生
saved you
为了你英雄救美
by blocking that knife.
又是挡刀的
Why don't you head back
还不赶紧回去
and take care of him?
照顾一下他
This is not the time
我跟你说这个时候
to act coy.
就不要再矜持了
Forget about the shirt.
什么还脱上衣
Just jump on him.
直接扑倒
Like fire meets wood.
干柴烈火
Have yourselves a night of tender love.
花前月下你侬我侬
A night you'll never forget.
回味无穷
Cut it.
闭嘴
You've been reading too much romance fiction.
你是不是小说看多了呀
That's where this nonsense is coming from.
老口出狂言
I'm being serious.
我跟你说认真的
A knife
刀
He blocked a knife for you.
那可是替你挡刀
This future husband of yours
你这未来的老公
definitely has feelings for you.
对你可真不简单
Xiaoning.
筱柠
Your hand's hurt.
你伤还没好呢
You should've stayed at home.
怎么不在家待着呀
I'm ok.
没事
You were out for a long time.
你出门这么久没回
And it's getting late.
又这么晚了
I was worried.
我不放心
I went to get some fruit.
我买了点水果
Let's go home.
回家吧
Take a walk home?
一起散个步
Sure.
好
Here.
来
Give it to me.
给我吧
But your hand's injured.
你手还受着伤呢
It's ok.
没事
I can use the other hand.
我用另一只手
So much
我觉得今天
has happened today.
真是发生了好多事情呀
What else
今天除了
besides the
动刀子的事之外
knife accident?
还有什么事
What's the matter?
怎么了
Would you still run over
如果今天早上
to save them
那个人不是我
if it hadn't been me
你也会
this morning?
跑过去救吗
I would.
会
But if it had been someone else,
但如果是别人的话
I'd save them cos I'm their boss.
我是作为上司
But it was you.
因为是你
I saved you not only because I'm your boss
除了作为上司
but because I'm your soon-to-be husband.
我更是你的准老公
Come on.
走吧
It feels nice
这个世界上
to have someone in this world
有一个愿意为自己
who's willing to
奋不顾身的人
sacrifice themselves
这种感觉
for you.
还不错嘛
The results are out.
成绩出来了
Excuse me.
不好意思 不好意思
I'm in the top 50.
我真考前五十名啊
Impressive.
厉害啊
Give me your phone.
快手机
Left mine in the classroom.
我放教室了
Let me take a picture
我拍一张照片
and send it to my mom.
赶紧给我妈发过去
That'll raise my
这回我的生活费呀
monthly allowance
必须得涨
for sure.
势在必得
But this is just the History score.
这是单科历史成绩
Not the total score.
又不是总分
It'll be fine.
没事儿
My mom is
我妈好对付
easy to fool.
她好骗
Why is Mr. Straight A
这学霸
only taking a picture of the History score?
怎么光拍历史成绩啊
Isn't that obvious?
还用说吗
his only weakness
学霸也就历史
is History.
稍微拖了点后腿
It's a reminder that
这肯定是拍下来
he needs to work on that.
警醒自己呗